Women's Liberation Collection, 1959-2006
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Women's liberation collection
1959-2006
1966-78
MS 408
26 boxes; 6 books (11 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
This collection documents the mid-20th century women's liberation movement in the United States. Materials include printed material, bibliographies, book reviews, books, catalogs, correspondence, position papers, publicity, questionnaires, reports, resolutions, speeches, photographs and audiotapes. There is also memorabilia and ephemera. Also included are organizational files of the National Organization for Women, and local groups such as New York City's Redstockings and Berkeley's Women's History Research Library, among others. Individuals represented in the collection include Ti-Grace Atkinson, Shulamith Firestone, Betty Friedan, Germaine Greer, Kate Millett, Robin Morgan and Gloria Steinem.
The Women's Liberation Collection documents the emergence, evolution, impact, and decline of the women's liberation movement and the contributions of some of the major personalities associated with it during the period 1966 to 1977. Material generated by the women's liberation movement includes bibliographies, book reviews, books, brochures, bumper stickers, audiotapes, catalogs, comic books, conference programs, correspondence, directories, leaflets, minutes, newsletters [see also Periodicals Collection], newspaper clippings, pamphlets, photographs, position papers, posters, publicity, questionnaires, reports, resolutions, songbooks, and speeches.
Individuals represented in the collection include Ti-Grace Atkinson, Shulamith Firestone, Betty Friedan, Germaine Greer, Kate Millett, Robin Morgan and Gloria Steinem. These individuals' files consist primarily of biographical information, newspapers clippings, and published writings, though a few also contain speeches and photographs. National organizations, such as the National Organization for Women are represented; as are local women's groups such as New York City's Redstockings and Berkeley's Women's History Research Library. Feminist groups associated with the Five Colleges and the Pioneer Valley are also well-represented in the collection.
Additional material includes published material and ephemera relating to a variety of issues that concerned feminists in the 1960s and 1970s. These cover the spectrum from anti-feminism to men's liberation to spirituality. Some of the more unique material includes both pornographic and anti-pornographic comic books; and "Consumer products" such as catalogs that document the wide array of t-shirts, bumper stickers, jewelry, buttons, postcards, and posters marketed to feminists. The collection also contains a large number of newspaper clippings from prominent mainstream publications such as the New York Times, Newsweek, Redbook, and Time Magazine documenting both unsympathetic cultural responses to women's liberation and the dramatic cultural shifts ushered in by feminists during their heyday in the 1970s.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The collection is open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
Additions to the Collection
Periodic additions to the collection are expected.
History of the Collection
Multiple donors have contributed to this collection.
Search Terms
Atkinson, Ti-Grace; Firestone, Shulamith; Friedan, Betty; Greer, Germaine, 1939-; Millett, Kate; Morgan, Robin; Steinem, Gloria.; National Organization for Women--History--Sources; Feminist Press -- History--Sources; Feminism in literature--History--20th century--Sources; Feminism--History--20th century--Sources; Lesbian feminism--History--Sources; Feminism--Massachusetts--History--20th century--Sources; Feminists--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Women in mass media--United States--History--20th century--Sources; Women's studies--History--20th century--Sources; Sophia Smith Collection
- INTERNATIONAL
  - Contents (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General
    - Clippings 1970-75 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The World's Girls: ABC News, 1963 (DVD) (Box 1, Folder 2a)
  - Arab countries, 1971-73, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Asia, 1970-75, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Australia and New Zealand, 1977-85 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Canada, 1971-80, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - China, 1970-72 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cuba, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - England, 1970-80 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Europe, 1970-73 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - France, 1970-76 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Germany, 1970-77 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ireland, 1971, n.d (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Israel, 1971-78 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mexico, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Soviet Union, 1970-78 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous, 1971-74 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- UNITED STATES
  - General articles and reprints: A-Z, 1969-74, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-8)
  - Bibliographies
    - General, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Articles, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Periodicals, 1970-79 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Sophia Smith Collection, 1979-70 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Bookstores and dealers 1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Feminist Book Mart, 1974-76 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Biography
    - Atkinson, Ti-Grace, 1968-74 [see also Subjects - Speeches] (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Firestone, Shulamith: Airless Spaces 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1a)
    - Friedan, Betty, 1963-81 [see also Orgs - NOW; and Subjects - Speeches] (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Greer, Germaine, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Millett, Kate, 1970-71 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Morgan, Robin, 1971-72 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Steinem, Gloria, 1969-82 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous women, 1975, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - General, 1970s, undated (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - Holyoke Transcript column, 1970-74 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - The Militant, 1970-71 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Western Massachusetts newspaper columns on and for women, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Catalogues
    - The Whole Women Catalog, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Women's Catalog, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Directories
    - Multi-service women's centers in New England, 1980, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Mushroom Effect, 1970-71 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Women's Action Alliance Directory, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Women's Centers: Where Are They?, 1974-79 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - The Women's List, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Guides
    - The People's Yellow Pages, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - The Women's Guide to Amherst-Northampton, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Women's Resource Guide, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Women's Resource Guide to Ithaca, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Women's Yellow Pages, 1974-78 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - State organizations
    - Alaska (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Arkansas (Box 7, Folder 1a)
    - California
      - American Friends Service Committee Women's Newsletter, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 1b)
      - Berkeley Women's Center, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Berkeley/Oakland Women's Union Newsletter, 1974-75 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Los Angeles Women's Center, 1970-72, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - San Diego Women's Center, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - San Francisco (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - San Jose Women's Center, 1974-76 (Box 7, Folder 6a)
      - Santa Cruz Women's Center, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6b)
      - Stanford Women's Center, 1972-78 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Sudsofloppen, San Francisco: Free Space: A Perspective on the Small Group in Women's Liberation by Pamela Allen, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 7a)
    - Colorado
      - Boulder County Women's Resource Center, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - University of Boulder, undated (Box 9)
    - Connecticut
      - Bristol: Connecticut Woman, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Hartford: Women's Lib Newsletter and Women's Voice, 1971-74 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - New Haven: Women's Lib Newsletter and Sister, 1969-75 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Norwalk: Women's Lib Center, 1972-73 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Storrs: University of Connecticut: Women's Center Information and paper, Atlanta, 1973-78 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Waterbury Area Women's Center, Inc. and ON OUR WAY,1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - District of Columbia
      - D.C. Area Feminist Alliance, 1978-79 (Box 8, Folder 1-1a)
      - Area Women's Center (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - The Georgetown Voice Magazine, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Liberation Newsletter, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Washington Women's Liberation, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Florida: Florida International University: Institute for Women,1973, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Georgia: Atalanta, (Atlanta) 1977 [see Periodicals] (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Illinois
      - Chicago (Box 8, Folder 8)
        - The Women's Forum Clearinghouse: International Newsletter, 1976 (Box 8)
        - Chicago Women's Liberation Union, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 8a)
        - Evanston Women's Liberation Center, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 8b)
        - Illinois Women's Agenda, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 9)
        - Illinois Women's Advocate, undated (Box 8)
      - New University Conference, 1970-71 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Indiana: Bloomington Women's Liberation, 1970-71 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Indiana: Fort Wayne Feminists, Joan Daley Uebelhoer, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 11a)
    - Louisiana: New Orleans: Southern Female Rights Union, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Maine: Maine Women's Newsletter, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Massachusetts
      - Amherst Women's Liberation (includes transcript of Pat Sackrey lecture, 1976): 1970-72 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Athol Women's Center, 1975-77 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Berkshires: Women's Liberation Newsletter, 1972-75 and Berkshire Women's News, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Cambridge
        - Cambridge Women's Center, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 4)
        - Cambridge Women's Center newsletter, On Our Way, 1971-75 (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - Cell 16 1971-75, undated (Box 9, Folder 5a)
          [see also Periodicals Collection: No More Fun and Games]
        - Women's Liberation Newsletter, 1969-70 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Cape Cod: Women's Liberation Newsletter, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Fall River: Bristol Community College: The Women's Center, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Franklin County Women's Coalition Journal, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Montachusett Women's Center, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - New Bedford Women's Center, 1977, 1985-86 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - North Adams: Women's Center, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Northampton: Common Womon Club, 1977-88 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - North Shore: Essecondsex (newsletter), 1971-73 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Pittsfield: Arachne's Loom, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 14a)
      - South Shore: Woman's Day, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Springfield: Women's Center Newsletter, 1972-75 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Worcester (Box 9, Folder 17)
        - Women's Press: UP Under, 1972-75; Worcester Connection, 1984 (Box 9)
      - Colleges and Universities
        - Greenfield Community College: Community Women's Center, 1972-75 (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Hampshire College: Women's Center News, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 1a)
        - Middlesex Community College: Women's Opportunity Research Center, 1976, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
          - Mount Holyoke College: Mount Holyoke Women's Center, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - North Dartmouth: Southeast Massachusetts University Women's Center, 1973, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
        - Smith College
          - Women's Liberation Newsletter, 1970-71 (Box 10, Folder 5)
          - Women's Resource Center, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 6)
          - Women's Resource Center Newsletter, 1975-82 (Box 10, Folder 7)
        - University of Massachusetts
          - Newsletters, general, 1970-73 (Box 10, Folder 8)
          - Newsletters, UMass Boston, 1977-78 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Michigan
      - Kalamazoo Women's Center: directory, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - University of Michigan
        - Center for Continuing Education Newsletter, 1970-73 (Box 11, Folder 1a)
        - The Feminine Mistake, 1970-71 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Northern Michigan University Women's Center, 1975-76 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Minnesota
      - Women's Center, 1974-75 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Twin Cities Women's Union, 1974-75 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Missouri: Kansas City Women's Liberation, 1970, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - New Hampshire
      - Littleton Women's Center, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Sisters, 1973, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - New Jersey
      - Rutger's Women's Caucus Newsletter, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - UPSALA College and YWCA Newsletter, 1974-75 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - New York
      - Barnard College Women's Center, 1972-79 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Brooklyn Bridge, 1971-72 (Box 12, Folder 5a)
      - Brooklyn: Union Center for Women, 1974-83 (Box 12, Folder 5b)
      - Bronx Women's Center, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 5c)
      - Buffalo Women's Center, 1973-74 (Box 12, Folder 5d)
      - The Feminists, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Fighting Woman News, 1978 [see Periodicals] (Box 12)
      - A History of the City Federation of Women's Organizations of Ithaca, NY, 1910-1969," and the Women's Community Building, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 7a)
      - Long Island Women's Liberation, 1969-70 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Redstockings, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Rochester: The Founding of Alternatives for Battered Women, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 9a)
      - Syracuse: Women's Information Center Newsletter, 1973-79, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - W.I.T.C.H., undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Women's Liberation Center of New York, 1972-73 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Ohio
    - Dayton Women's Center: newsletter and directory, 1974-75 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Ohio State University: Women Are Human, 1973 [see Periodicals Collection] (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Pennsylvania
    - Bucks County Women's Caucus, 1973-74 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Harrisburg Area Women's Center (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Philadelphia Women's Liberation Center, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Pittsburgh Women's Center, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Women's Resource Center: Reading, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 17a)
  - Tennessee: Nashville Women's Alliance, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 17b)
  - Texas
    - SMU Women's Center, 1974-75 (Box 18)
      - Amarillo, 1978 (Box 18)
    - Utah: Rocky Mountain Woman, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Washington
      - Seattle Lesbian Feminist, 1981-82 (Box 12A, Folder 1a)
      - Seattle Radical Woman, 1970-75 (Box 12A, Folder 1b)
    - Wisconsin: Milwaukee, 1975 (Box 12A, Folder 1c)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-84 (Box 12A, Folder 2)
  - National organizations
    - National Organization for Women
      - By-laws, statements of purpose, and letters to officials, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Communications to members, 1967-80 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, blanks, etc., 1970-74 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Memoranda, 1973, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - National Conferences
        - Washington, DC, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 5)
        - Atlanta, GA, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 6)
        - Chicago, IL, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 7)
        - Los Angeles, CA, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 8)
        - Washington, DC, 1973, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
      - Clippings, printed material, memorabilia, 1968-80, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - How It Began, by Betty Friedan and The First Five Years,1966-73 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Majority Caucus, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - Newspaper and magazine articles (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - Press releases, 1966-78 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - Reports of the president, committees, and workshops, 1966-77 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Task forces
        - Business and Industry Compliance and Enforcement, 1971-73 (Box 14, Folder 2)
        - Compliance and Enforcement, 1973-75 (Box 14, Folder 3)
        - Finance and Credit, 1973-75, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
        - Legal and Political Rights, 1975, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
        - Image of Women in Media and Public Relations, 1971-75 (Box 14, Folder 6)
        - Marriage, Divorce and Family Relations, 1973-75 (Box 14, Folder 7)
        - Miscellaneous, 1967-75 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - N.O.W. local chapter directory, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - State chapters
        - California
          - General, 1969-73 (Box 15, Folder 2)
          - Los Angeles, 1973-78 (Box 15, Folder 3)
          - Pomona Valley, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 4)
          - San Diego, 1975-78 (Box 15, Folder 5)
        - Florida, 1973-75 (Box 15, Folder 6)
        - Georgia, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 7)
        - Illinois, 1972-73 (Box 15, Folder 8)
        - Louisiana, 1973-74 (Box 15, Folder 9)
        - Maryland, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 10)
        - Massachusetts
          - General, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 11)
          - Springfield, 1975-83 (Box 15, Folder 12)
        - Michigan, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 13)
        - Nebraska, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 14)
        - Nevada, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 15)
        - New Jersey
          - Middlesex County, 1978-79 (Box 15, Folder 16)
          - Northern New Jersey, 1971-72 (Box 15, Folder 17)
        - New Mexico, 1970-73 (Box 15, Folder 18)
        - Pennsylvania: Pittsburgh, 1970-71 (Box 15, Folder 19)
        - Rhode Island, 1973-74 (Box 15, Folder 20)
        - Tennessee, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 21)
        - Texas, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 22)
        - West Virginia, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 22a)
        - Wisconsin, 1970-72 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Presses and publishers
    - Presses, general, 1970-78, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - The Feminist Press, 1972-83 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Helaine Victoria Press, 1980-83 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Know, Inc., 1971-74, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Know Publications Lists, 1971-76 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Know - Tuning Into the Women's Movement, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Gabrielle Burton, I'm Running Away… (Know, Inc., 1972) [on shelf] (Box 16)
    - Women's History Research Center Library, 1971-75, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets and position papers
    - "Notes from the First Year," New York Radical Women, June 1968 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - "Notes from the Second Year," New York Radical Women, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Notes from the Third Year," New York Radical Women, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "Notes on Women's Liberation: We Speak in Many Voices," issued by News and Letters, Detroit, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Pamphlets
      - 1968-75 (Box 18, Folder 5-9)
      - 1976-90, undated (Box 18A, Folder 1-4)
    - Position papers, 1969-74, undated (Box 18A, Folder 5-8)
  - Subjects
    - Anti-feminism Game, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Assertiveness training, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Anti-feminist, 1969-73 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Book reviews, 1969-73 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Cartoons, humor, undated [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Conferences
      - Clippings, 1970-71 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - General, 1970-82 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Northeast
        - Cornell Conference on Women, Jan 1969 (Box 20, Folder 5)
        - Smith College Symposium on Women's Role in Society, Feb 1970 (Box 20, Folder 6)
        - University of Massachusetts Women's Conference, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 7)
        - University of Pittsburgh Symposium on Feminism, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - International
        - General, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 9)
        - International Feminist Planning Council, Jun 1973 (Box 20, Folder 10)
        - International Tribunal on Crimes Against Women,1975-76 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Consciousness training, 1970-75, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Consumer products: bumper stickers, calendars, catalogs, and other memorabilia 1971-77, undated [see also Flat File] (Box 21, Folder 1-5)
    - Divisiveness in the movement, 1970-74 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - International Women's Day, 1959-75 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Language, 1971-81 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Maiden name controversy, 1970-73 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Media
      - Image of women in television, 1972-74 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Women and the media, 1970-80, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Radio documentary, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Women's Film Coop: catalogs, 1972-73 (Box 22, Folder 6a)
    - Men's liberation
      - General, 1969-82, undated (Box 23, Folder 1-3)
      - Clippings, 1970-72 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Men's Studies: bibliography 1977, undated (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
    - Misandry and misogyny, 1969-72 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Music [see Music Collection] (Box 23)
    - Older Women's Liberation, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Political action, 1972, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Pornography
      - General, 1978-2006, undated (Box 23, Folder 10-11)
      - Comic books, undated (Box 23, Folder 12-13)
    - Protest actions
      - General, 1970-72, n.d (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - Clippings, 1970-77, undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - Take Back the Night, 1978-79, undated (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Public opinion polls, 1970-72 (Box 23A, Folder 1)
    - Public speaking and speakers, 1970 (Box 23A, Folder 2)
    - Revolution, 1969-75, undated (Box 23A, Folder 3)
    - Self Defense, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 1a)
    - Sexism
      - General, 1970-79 (Box 24, Folder 1b)
      - Advertising, 1970-89 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Beauty contests, 1971-72 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Children's literature, 1970-75 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Children's television, 1972, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Toys, 1971-72 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Songs, 1971, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Speeches: Rossi Marlene Dixon, Germaine Bree, Betty Friedan, Ti-Grace Atkinson (audiotape), 1969-72 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Spirituality [see also Books] (Box 24, Folder 8a)
    - Young women, 1969-73 (Box 24, Folder 9)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Miscellaneous posters and bumper stickers (Map-case Flat file drawer 6)
  - Cartoon from "Puck: At the Emancipated Women's Club" 1896 (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
  - States: California, San Francisco (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
    - San Francisco Survival Manual, Spr 1978 (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
    - The Women's Street Theater, "This is a Cranky…," undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
  - States: Florida, Tallahassee Feminist History Project issue of Spectrum: A Cooperative Newspaper for the Tallahassee Community, Issue no. 28, Winter Solstice, 1981 (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
  - Subjects, Political Actions (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
    - Lucy Parsons Women's Coalition broadside, circa 1972 (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
    - Poster for Women's Liberation Day, Boston, 1972 (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
  - Posters for Pioneer Valley and Five College women's events, 1970-82, undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
  - Poster: "100 Simple Things You Can Do To End PATRIARCHY," 1991 (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
  - Mounted poster of Cartoon: "Occupation? Woman," undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
  - Posters (general): publishers include Les Femmes; Times Change Press; NOW; Chicago Women's Liberation, circa 1970s-80s (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
  - "Salute to Women," World Magazine, March 7, 1970 (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
  - Miscellaneous posters (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
    - "Sister Love," undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
    - "Witches," undated (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
    - "Freedom," circa 1970 (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
    - "May Day," circa 1971 (Map-case Flat file drawer 7)
  - Poster: "GIRLS SAY YES to boys who say NO. Proceeds from the sale of this poster go to The Draft Resistance," 435 Baez Girls circa 1968 (Map-case Flat file drawer 26)
- BOOKS
  - The Holy Book of Women's Mysteries by Zsuzsanna E. Budapest, 1979 (Box 25)
  - Earth Rites: Vol. 2: Rituals, Sherry Mestes, Ed., 1978 (Box 25)
  - In Defense of Ourselves by Linda T. Sanford and Ann Felter, 1979 (Box 25)